<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zoo animals on The network zoo</title>
    <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zoo animals on The network zoo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 08:50:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MONSTER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/monster/</guid>
      <description>Reference Estimating drivers of cell state transitions using gene regulatory network models.
Daniel Schlauch, Kimberly Glass, Craig P Hersh, Edwin K Silverman, John Quackenbush
BMC Systems Biology
doi.org/10.1186/s12918-017-0517-y
Abstract Background: Specific cellular states are often associated with distinct gene expression patterns. These states are plastic, changing during development, or in the transition from health to disease. One relatively simple extension of this concept is to recognize that we can classify different cell-types by their active gene regulatory networks and that, consequently, transitions between cellular states can be modeled by changes in these underlying regulatory networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAMBAR</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/sambar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/sambar/</guid>
      <description>Reference Cancer subtype identification using somatic mutation data.
Marieke Lydia Kuijjer, Joseph Nathaniel Paulson, Peter Salzman, Wei Ding, and John Quackenbush
British Journal of Cancer
doi.org/10.1038/s41416-018-0109-7
Abstract Background: With the onset of next-generation sequencing technologies, we have made great progress in identifying recurrent mutational drivers of cancer. As cancer tissues are now frequently screened for specific sets of mutations, a large amount of samples has become available for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gpuZoo</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/gpuzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/gpuzoo/</guid>
      <description>Reference gpuZoo: Cost-effective estimation of gene regulatory networks using the Graphics Processing Unit.
Marouen Ben Guebila, Daniel C Morgan, Kimberly Glass, Marieke L. Kuijjer, Dawn L. DeMeo, John Quackenbush
NAR Genomics and Bioinformatics
doi.org/10.1093/nargab/lqac002
Abstract Gene regulatory network inference allows for the modeling of genome-scale regulatory processes that are altered during development, in disease, and in response to perturbations. Our group has developed a collection of tools to model various regulatory processes, including transcriptional (PANDA, SPIDER) and post-transcriptional (PUMA) gene regulation, as well as gene regulation in individual samples (LIONESS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRAGON</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/dragon/</guid>
      <description>Reference DRAGON: Determining Regulatory Associations using Graphical models on multi-Omic Networks
Katherine H Shutta, Deborah Weighill, Rebekka Burkholz, Marouen Ben Guebila, Dawn L DeMeo, Helena U Zacharias, John Quackenbush, Michael Altenbuchinger
OUP Nucleic Acids Research
10.1093/nar/gkac1157
Abstract The increasing quantity of multi-omic data, such as methylomic and transcriptomic profiles collected on the same specimen or even on the same cell, provides a unique opportunity to explore the complex interactions that define cell phenotype and govern cellular responses to perturbations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIGER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/tiger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/tiger/</guid>
      <description>Reference Flexible modeling of regulatory networksimproves transcription factor activity estimation
Chen Chen, Megha Padi
npj Systems Biology and Applications
doi.org/10.1038/s41540-024-00386-w
Abstract Transcriptional regulation plays a crucial role in determining cell fate and disease, yet inferring the key regulators from gene expression data remains a significant challenge. Existing methods for estimating transcription factor (TF) activity often rely on static TF-gene interaction databases and cannot adapt to changes in regulatory mechanisms across different cell types and disease conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>