<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zoo animals on The network zoo</title>
    <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zoo animals on The network zoo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 08:50:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LIONESS</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/lioness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/lioness/</guid>
      <description>Reference Estimating Sample-Specific Regulatory Networks.
Marieke Lydia Kuijjer, Matthew George Tung, Guo Cheng Yuan, John Quackenbush, Kimberly Glass.
iScience
doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2019.03.021.
Abstract Biological systems are driven by intricate interactions among molecules. Many methods have been developed that draw on large numbers of expression samples to infer connections between genes (or their products). The result is an aggregate network representing a single estimate for the likelihood of each interaction, or “edge,” in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MONSTER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/monster/</guid>
      <description>Reference Estimating drivers of cell state transitions using gene regulatory network models.
Daniel Schlauch, Kimberly Glass, Craig P Hersh, Edwin K Silverman, John Quackenbush.
BMC Systems Biology
doi.org/10.1186/s12918-017-0517-y.
Abstract Background: Specific cellular states are often associated with distinct gene expression patterns. These states are plastic, changing during development, or in the transition from health to disease. One relatively simple extension of this concept is to recognize that we can classify different cell-types by their active gene regulatory networks and that, consequently, transitions between cellular states can be modeled by changes in these underlying regulatory networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAMBAR</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/sambar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/sambar/</guid>
      <description>Reference Cancer subtype identification using somatic mutation data.
Marieke Lydia Kuijjer, Joseph Nathaniel Paulson, Peter Salzman, Wei Ding, and John Quackenbush.
British Journal of Cancer
doi.org/10.1038/s41416-018-0109-7.
Abstract Background: With the onset of next-generation sequencing technologies, we have made great progress in identifying recurrent mutational drivers of cancer. As cancer tissues are now frequently screened for specific sets of mutations, a large amount of samples has become available for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gpuZoo</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/gpuzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/gpuzoo/</guid>
      <description>Reference gpuZoo: Cost-effective estimation of gene regulatory networks using the Graphics Processing Unit.
Marouen Ben Guebila, Daniel C Morgan, Kimberly Glass, Marieke L. Kuijjer, Dawn L. DeMeo, John Quackenbush.
NAR Genomics and Bioinformatics
doi.org/10.1093/nargab/lqac002.
Abstract Gene regulatory network inference allows for the modeling of genome-scale regulatory processes that are altered during development, in disease, and in response to perturbations. Our group has developed a collection of tools to model various regulatory processes, including transcriptional (PANDA, SPIDER) and post-transcriptional (PUMA) gene regulation, as well as gene regulation in individual samples (LIONESS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRAGON</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/dragon/</guid>
      <description>Reference DRAGON: Determining Regulatory Associations using Graphical models on multi-Omic Networks
Katherine H Shutta, Deborah Weighill, Rebekka Burkholz, Marouen Ben Guebila, Dawn L DeMeo, Helena U Zacharias, John Quackenbush, Michael Altenbuchinger
OUP Nucleic Acids Research
10.1093/nar/gkac1157
Abstract The increasing quantity of multi-omic data, such as methylomic and transcriptomic profiles collected on the same specimen or even on the same cell, provides a unique opportunity to explore the complex interactions that define cell phenotype and govern cellular responses to perturbations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YARN</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/yarn/</guid>
      <description>Reference Tissue-aware RNA-Seq processing and normalization for heterogeneous and sparse data
Joseph N. Paulson, Cho-Yi Chen, Camila M. Lopes-Ramos, Marieke L. Kuijjer, John Platig, Abhijeet R. Sonawane, Maud Fagny, Kimberly Glass &amp;amp; John Quackenbush
BMC Bioinformatics
doi.org/10.1186/s12859-017-1847-x
Abstract Background
Although ultrahigh-throughput RNA-Sequencing has become the dominant technology for genome-wide transcriptional profiling, the vast majority of RNA-Seq studies typically profile only tens of samples, and most analytical pipelines are optimized for these smaller studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIGER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/tiger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/tiger/</guid>
      <description>Reference Joint inference of transcription factor activity and context-specific regulatory networks
Chen Chen, Megha Padi
bioRxiv
doi.org/10.1101/2022.12.12.520141
Abstract Transcriptional regulation is a critical process that determines cell fate and disease. One of the challenges in understanding transcriptional regulation is that there is no easy way to infer the main regulators from gene expression data. Many existing methods focus on estimating the activity of individual transcription factors (TFs) using static TF-gene interaction databases, but regulomes are often altered in different cell types and disease conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COBRA</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/cobra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/cobra/</guid>
      <description>Reference Higher-order correction of persistent batch effects in correlation networks
Soel Micheletti, Daniel Schlauch, John Quackenbush, Marouen Ben Guebila
bioRxiv
doi.org/10.1101/2023.12.28.573533
Abstract Systems biology methods often rely on correlations in gene expression profiles to infer co-expression networks, commonly used as input for gene regulatory network inference or to identify functional modules of co-expressed or co-regulated genes. While systematic biases, including batch effects, are known to induce spurious associations and confound differential gene expression analyses (DE), the impact of batch effects on gene co-expression has not been fully explored.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>