<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Network pre-processing on The network zoo</title>
    <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/preproc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Network pre-processing on The network zoo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 08:50:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/preproc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>YARN</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/preproc/yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/preproc/yarn/</guid>
      <description>Reference Tissue-aware RNA-Seq processing and normalization for heterogeneous and sparse data
Joseph N. Paulson, Cho-Yi Chen, Camila M. Lopes-Ramos, Marieke L. Kuijjer, John Platig, Abhijeet R. Sonawane, Maud Fagny, Kimberly Glass &amp;amp; John Quackenbush
BMC Bioinformatics
doi.org/10.1186/s12859-017-1847-x
Abstract Background
Although ultrahigh-throughput RNA-Sequencing has become the dominant technology for genome-wide transcriptional profiling, the vast majority of RNA-Seq studies typically profile only tens of samples, and most analytical pipelines are optimized for these smaller studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COBRA</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/preproc/cobra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/preproc/cobra/</guid>
      <description>Reference Higher-order correction of persistent batch effects in correlation networks
Soel Micheletti, Daniel Schlauch, John Quackenbush, Marouen Ben Guebila
bioRxiv
doi.org/10.1101/2023.12.28.573533
Abstract Systems biology methods often rely on correlations in gene expression profiles to infer co-expression networks, commonly used as input for gene regulatory network inference or to identify functional modules of co-expressed or co-regulated genes. While systematic biases, including batch effects, are known to induce spurious associations and confound differential gene expression analyses (DE), the impact of batch effects on gene co-expression has not been fully explored.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>