<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The network zoo</title>
    <link>https://netZoo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The network zoo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://netZoo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/contribute/</guid>
      <description>Contribution guide The netZoo is an open-source software suite of network biology methods in R, Python, MATLAB, and C. Contributions to the netZoo can be in the form of 1) bug fixing, 2) performance improvment, and 3) new functions.
Each language repository has a master and a devel branch. The master branch contains the stable code of the netZoo, and the devel branch contains the code with the new features that gets periodically merged into the master branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute to Netbooks</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/contributenetbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/contributenetbooks/</guid>
      <description>Contribution guide netbooks is a Jupyter notebook tutorial server that hosts several uses case of the Network Zoo tools.
Preparing the contribution Please prepare your tutorial as an Python/R Jupyter notebook.
Make sure to:
  Avoid saving files on disk
  Avoid making systems calls to create folders or call other programs such as os.system( someBashCommand )
  Include substantial documentation of the code and illustrate the use cases with biological/theoretical motivation in the introduction and main takeaway in the conclusion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/install/</guid>
      <description>Installation guide To install netZoo{Py, M, C}, all you have to do is git clone https://github.com/netZoo/netZoo{Py,M,C}.git then to get the latest changes in your repository you need to git pull origin master.
You can work on the devel branch by git checkout devel. To update the devel branch type git pull origin devel.
In Python, an additional step is required to install netZooPy through pip3 install -e . in the either the root of devel or master branch and after each change to the source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/docs/docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/docs/docs/</guid>
      <description>netZooR:
 Link to the dedicated documentation website.
netZooPy:
 Link to the dedicated documentation website.
netZooM:
 Link to the dedicated documentation website.
netZooC:
 Link to the dedicated documentation website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/papers/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/papers/papers/</guid>
      <description>Publications PANDA  Gene co-expression analysis for functional classification and gene–disease predictions. S Van Dam and U Vosa and A van der Graaf….
 https://academic.oup.com/bib/article-abstract/19/4/575/2888441.
 Biomarker development in the precision medicine era: lung cancer as a case study. AJ Vargas and CC Harris.
 https://idp.nature.com/authorize/casa?redirect_uri=https://www.nature.com/articles/nrc.2016.56.pdf%3Forigin%3Dppub&amp;amp;casa_token=HLEJOmMbcEYAAAAA:iB71mDAuA_eDTgYqzPI4K-CWrYviZQr-xKCIBCgV1j6LJQm9M3ahV0zRnv0K0iakt1crPVyc6w5G7zgGkA.
 Understanding tissue-specific gene regulation. AR Sonawane and J Platig and M Fagny and CY Chen….
 https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211124717314183.
 DIABLO: an integrative approach for identifying key molecular drivers from multi-omics assays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting help</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/issues/</guid>
      <description>Issues If you need help or if you have any question about netZoo, please check discussions.
If you would like to report a bug in the netZoo, please open an issue in the issues tab of the corresponding netZoo{R,Py,M,C} github.
Tutorials Check the tutorials in the github repo for a basic application of the network tools.
netZooPy: Jupyter Notebook Tutorials.
netZooM: LiveScript Tutorials.
netZooR: R markdown Tutorials.
Abbreviations The Network Zoo ecosystem tools are abbreviated as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIONESS</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/ss/lioness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/ss/lioness/</guid>
      <description>Reference Estimating Sample-Specific Regulatory Networks.
Marieke Lydia Kuijjer, Matthew George Tung, Guo Cheng Yuan, John Quackenbush, Kimberly Glass
iScience
doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2019.03.021
Abstract Biological systems are driven by intricate interactions among molecules. Many methods have been developed that draw on large numbers of expression samples to infer connections between genes (or their products). The result is an aggregate network representing a single estimate for the likelihood of each interaction, or “edge,” in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BONOBO</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/ss/bonobo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/ss/bonobo/</guid>
      <description>Reference Bayesian inference of sample-specific coexpression networks
Enakshi Saha, Viola Fanfani, Panagiotis Mandros, Marouen Ben Guebila, Jonas Fischer, Katherine Hoff-Shutta, Dawn Lisa DeMeo, Camila Lopes-Ramos, John Quackenbush
Genome Research
doi.org/10.1101/gr.279117.124
Abstract Gene regulatory networks (GRNs) are effective tools for inferring complex interactions between molecules that regulate biological processes and hence can provide insights into drivers of biological systems. Inferring coexpression networks is a critical element of GRN inference, as the correlation between expression patterns may indicate that genes are coregulated by common factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MONSTER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/monster/</guid>
      <description>Reference Estimating drivers of cell state transitions using gene regulatory network models.
Daniel Schlauch, Kimberly Glass, Craig P Hersh, Edwin K Silverman, John Quackenbush
BMC Systems Biology
doi.org/10.1186/s12918-017-0517-y
Abstract Background: Specific cellular states are often associated with distinct gene expression patterns. These states are plastic, changing during development, or in the transition from health to disease. One relatively simple extension of this concept is to recognize that we can classify different cell-types by their active gene regulatory networks and that, consequently, transitions between cellular states can be modeled by changes in these underlying regulatory networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAMBAR</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/sambar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/sambar/</guid>
      <description>Reference Cancer subtype identification using somatic mutation data.
Marieke Lydia Kuijjer, Joseph Nathaniel Paulson, Peter Salzman, Wei Ding, and John Quackenbush
British Journal of Cancer
doi.org/10.1038/s41416-018-0109-7
Abstract Background: With the onset of next-generation sequencing technologies, we have made great progress in identifying recurrent mutational drivers of cancer. As cancer tissues are now frequently screened for specific sets of mutations, a large amount of samples has become available for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gpuZoo</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/gpuzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/gpuzoo/</guid>
      <description>Reference gpuZoo: Cost-effective estimation of gene regulatory networks using the Graphics Processing Unit.
Marouen Ben Guebila, Daniel C Morgan, Kimberly Glass, Marieke L. Kuijjer, Dawn L. DeMeo, John Quackenbush
NAR Genomics and Bioinformatics
doi.org/10.1093/nargab/lqac002
Abstract Gene regulatory network inference allows for the modeling of genome-scale regulatory processes that are altered during development, in disease, and in response to perturbations. Our group has developed a collection of tools to model various regulatory processes, including transcriptional (PANDA, SPIDER) and post-transcriptional (PUMA) gene regulation, as well as gene regulation in individual samples (LIONESS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRAGON</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/dragon/</guid>
      <description>Reference DRAGON: Determining Regulatory Associations using Graphical models on multi-Omic Networks
Katherine H Shutta, Deborah Weighill, Rebekka Burkholz, Marouen Ben Guebila, Dawn L DeMeo, Helena U Zacharias, John Quackenbush, Michael Altenbuchinger
OUP Nucleic Acids Research
10.1093/nar/gkac1157
Abstract The increasing quantity of multi-omic data, such as methylomic and transcriptomic profiles collected on the same specimen or even on the same cell, provides a unique opportunity to explore the complex interactions that define cell phenotype and govern cellular responses to perturbations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIGER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/tiger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/tiger/</guid>
      <description>Reference Flexible modeling of regulatory networks improves transcription factor activity estimation
Chen Chen, Megha Padi
npj Systems Biology and Applications
doi.org/10.1038/s41540-024-00386-w
Abstract Transcriptional regulation plays a crucial role in determining cell fate and disease, yet inferring the key regulators from gene expression data remains a significant challenge. Existing methods for estimating transcription factor (TF) activity often rely on static TF-gene interaction databases and cannot adapt to changes in regulatory mechanisms across different cell types and disease conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/gsoc25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/gsoc25/</guid>
      <description>Clicking this willopenthe sidebar.Sidebar Closed Your Library Harvard logo
Ideas List, Google Summer of Code 2025  Ideas List, Google Summer of Code 2025  FAQ  What is the netZoo project? Who should apply to be a contributor? Who is gonna mentor the project? How have we chosen these projects?   Ideas  Idea #1: Standardization of interfaces, inputs and outputs Idea #2: Unit tests Idea #3: Migrate GRAND database to secure and updated technology stacks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>