<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The network zoo</title>
    <link>https://netZoo.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The network zoo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://netZoo.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>List</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/animals/</guid>
      <description>Network biology PANDA:
 paper (netZooR, netZooPy, netZooM, netZooC)
LIONESS:
 paper (netZooR, netZooPy, netZooM)
CONDOR:
 paper (netZooR, netZooPy)
MONSTER:
 paper (netZooR)
ALPACA:
 paper (netZooR)
PUMA:
 paper (netZooPy, netZooM, netZooC)
SAMBAR:
 paper (netZooR, netZooPy)
SPIDER:
 paper (netZooM)
OTTER:
 paper (netZooR, netZooPy, netZooM)
CRANE:
 paper (netZooR)
EGRET:
 paper (netZooR)
DRAGON:
 paper (netZooPy)
Sequence analysis YARN:
 paper (netZooR)
FENRIR:
 In preparation - repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/contribute/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/contribute/</guid>
      <description>Contribution guide The netZoo is an open-source software suite of network biology methods in R, Python, MATLAB, and C. Contributions to the netZoo can be in the form of 1) bug fixing, 2) performance improvment, and 3) new functions.
Each language repository has a master and a devel branch. The master branch contains the stable code of the netZoo, and the devel branch contains the code with the new features that gets periodically merged into the master branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to contribute to netbooks</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/contributenetbooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/contributenetbooks/</guid>
      <description>Contribution guide netbooks is a Jupyter notebook tutorial server that hosts several uses case of the Network Zoo tools.
Preparing the contribution Please prepare your tutorial as an Python/R Jupyter notebook.
Make sure to:
  Avoid saving files on disk
  Avoid making systems calls to create folders or call other programs such as os.system( someBashCommand )
  Include substantial documentation of the code and illustrate the use cases with biological/theoretical motivation in the introduction and main takeaway in the conclusion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/install/</guid>
      <description>Installation guide To install netZoo{Py, M, C}, all you have to do is git clone https://github.com/netZoo/netZoo{Py,M,C}.git then to get the latest changes in your repository you need to git pull origin master.
You can work on the devel branch by git checkout devel. To update the devel branch type git pull origin devel.
In Python, an additional step is required to install netZooPy through pip3 install -e . in the either the root of devel or master branch and after each change to the source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/docs/docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/docs/docs/</guid>
      <description>netZooR:
 Link to the dedicated documentation website.
netZooPy:
 Link to the dedicated documentation website.
netZooM:
 Link to the dedicated documentation website.
netZooC:
 Link to the dedicated documentation website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/papers/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/papers/papers/</guid>
      <description>Publications PANDA  Gene co-expression analysis for functional classification and gene–disease predictions. S Van Dam and U Vosa and A van der Graaf….
 https://academic.oup.com/bib/article-abstract/19/4/575/2888441.
 Biomarker development in the precision medicine era: lung cancer as a case study. AJ Vargas and CC Harris.
 https://idp.nature.com/authorize/casa?redirect_uri=https://www.nature.com/articles/nrc.2016.56.pdf%3Forigin%3Dppub&amp;amp;casa_token=HLEJOmMbcEYAAAAA:iB71mDAuA_eDTgYqzPI4K-CWrYviZQr-xKCIBCgV1j6LJQm9M3ahV0zRnv0K0iakt1crPVyc6w5G7zgGkA.
 Understanding tissue-specific gene regulation. AR Sonawane and J Platig and M Fagny and CY Chen….
 https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2211124717314183.
 DIABLO: an integrative approach for identifying key molecular drivers from multi-omics assays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PANDA</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/panda/panda/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/panda/panda/</guid>
      <description>Reference Passing Messages between Biological Networks to Refine Predicted Interactions.
Kimberly Glass, Curtis Huttenhower, John Quackenbush, Guo-Cheng Yuan.
Plos One
doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0064832.
Abstract Regulatory network reconstruction is a fundamental problem in computational biology. There are significant limitations to such reconstruction using individual datasets, and increasingly people attempt to construct networks using multiple, independent datasets obtained from complementary sources, but methods for this integration are lacking. We developed PANDA (Passing Attributes between Networks for Data Assimilation), a message-passing model using multiple sources of information to predict regulatory relationships, and used it to integrate protein-protein interaction, gene expression, and sequence motif data to reconstruct genome-wide, condition-specific regulatory networks in yeast as a model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting help</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/contribute/issues/</guid>
      <description>Issues If you need help or if you have any question about netZoo, please check discussions.
If you would like to report a bug in the netZoo, please open an issue in the issues tab of the corresponding netZoo{R,Py,M,C} github.
Tutorials Check the tutorials in the github repo for a basic application of the network tools.
netZooPy: Jupyter Notebook Tutorials.
netZooM: LiveScript Tutorials.
netZooR: R markdown Tutorials.
Abbreviations The Network Zoo ecosystem tools are abbreviated as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LIONESS</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/lioness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/lioness/</guid>
      <description>Reference Estimating Sample-Specific Regulatory Networks.
Marieke Lydia Kuijjer, Matthew George Tung, Guo Cheng Yuan, John Quackenbush, Kimberly Glass.
iScience
doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2019.03.021.
Abstract Biological systems are driven by intricate interactions among molecules. Many methods have been developed that draw on large numbers of expression samples to infer connections between genes (or their products). The result is an aggregate network representing a single estimate for the likelihood of each interaction, or “edge,” in the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CONDOR</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/condor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/condor/</guid>
      <description>Reference Bipartite Community Structure of eQTLs.
John Platig, Peter J. Castaldi, Dawn DeMeo, John Quackenbush.
Plos computational biology
doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1005033.
Abstract Genome Wide Association Studies (GWAS) and expression quantitative trait locus (eQTL) analyses have identified genetic associations with a wide range of human phenotypes. However, many of these variants have weak effects and understanding their combined effect remains a challenge. One hypothesis is that multiple SNPs interact in complex networks to influence functional processes that ultimately lead to complex phenotypes, including disease states.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MONSTER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/monster/</guid>
      <description>Reference Estimating drivers of cell state transitions using gene regulatory network models.
Daniel Schlauch, Kimberly Glass, Craig P Hersh, Edwin K Silverman, John Quackenbush.
BMC Systems Biology
doi.org/10.1186/s12918-017-0517-y.
Abstract Background: Specific cellular states are often associated with distinct gene expression patterns. These states are plastic, changing during development, or in the transition from health to disease. One relatively simple extension of this concept is to recognize that we can classify different cell-types by their active gene regulatory networks and that, consequently, transitions between cellular states can be modeled by changes in these underlying regulatory networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALPACA</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/alpaca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/alpaca/</guid>
      <description>Reference Detecting phenotype-driven transitions in regulatory network structure.
Megha Padi and John Quackenbush.
npj Systems biology and applications
doi:10.1038/s41540-018-0052-5.
Abstract Complex traits and diseases like human height or cancer are often not caused by a single mutation or genetic variant, but instead arise from functional changes in the underlying molecular network. Biological networks are known to be highly modular and contain dense “communities” of genes that carry out cellular processes, but these structures change between tissues, during development, and in disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PUMA</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/panda/puma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/panda/puma/</guid>
      <description>Reference PUMA: PANDA Using MicroRNA Associations.
Marieke L Kuijjer, Maud Fagny, Alessandro Marin, John Quackenbush, Kimberly Glass.
OUP Bioinformatics
doi.org/10.1093/bioinformatics/btaa571.
Abstract Conventional methods to analyze genomic data do not make use of the interplay between multiple factors, such as between microRNAs (miRNAs) and the mRNA transcripts they regulate, and thereby often fail to identify the cellular processes that are unique to specific tissues. We developed PUMA (PANDA Using MicroRNA Associations), a computational tool that uses message passing to integrate a prior network of miRNA target predictions with target gene co-expression information to model genome-wide gene regulation by miRNAs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAMBAR</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/sambar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/sambar/</guid>
      <description>Reference Cancer subtype identification using somatic mutation data.
Marieke Lydia Kuijjer, Joseph Nathaniel Paulson, Peter Salzman, Wei Ding, and John Quackenbush.
British Journal of Cancer
doi.org/10.1038/s41416-018-0109-7.
Abstract Background: With the onset of next-generation sequencing technologies, we have made great progress in identifying recurrent mutational drivers of cancer. As cancer tissues are now frequently screened for specific sets of mutations, a large amount of samples has become available for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OTTER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/otter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/otter/</guid>
      <description>Reference Gene Regulatory Network Inference as Relaxed Graph Matching.
Deborah Weighill, Marouen Ben Guebila, Camila Lopes-Ramos, Kimberly Glass, John Quackenbush, John Platig, Rebekka Burkholz.
Proceedings of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence
doi.org/10.1101/2020.06.23.167999.
Abstract Gene regulatory network inference is instrumental to the discovery of genetic mechanisms driving diverse diseases, including cancer. Here, we present a theoretical framework for PANDA, an established method for gene regulatory network inference. PANDA is based on iterative message passing updates that resemble the gradient descent of an optimization problem, OTTER, which can be interpreted as relaxed inexact graph matching between a gene-gene co-expression and a protein-protein interaction matrix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRANE</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/crane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/crane/</guid>
      <description>Reference Generating Ensembles of Gene Regulatory Networks to Assess Robustness of Disease Modules.
James T. Lim, Chen Chen, Adam D. Grant, Megha Padi.
Frontiers in Genetics
doi.org/10.3389/fgene.2020.603264.
Abstract The use of biological networks such as protein-protein interaction and transcriptional regulatory networks is becoming an integral part of biological research in the genomics era. However, these networks are not static, and during phenotypic transitions like disease onset, they can acquire new “communities” of genes that carry out key cellular processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPIDER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/panda/spider/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 08:49:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/panda/spider/</guid>
      <description>Reference Constructing Gene Regulatory Networks using Epigenetic Data
Abhijeet Rajendra Sonawane, Dawn L. DeMeo, John Quackenbush, Kimberly Glass.
bioRxiv
doi.org/10.1101/2020.10.19.345827.
Abstract The biological processes that drive cellular function can be represented by a complex network of interactions between regulators (transcription factors) and their targets (genes). A cell’s epigenetic state plays an important role in mediating these interactions, primarily by influencing chromatin accessibility. However, effectively leveraging epigenetic information when constructing regulatory networks remains a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gpuZoo</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/gpuzoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/gpuzoo/</guid>
      <description>Reference gpuZoo: Cost-effective estimation of gene regulatory networks using the Graphics Processing Unit.
Marouen Ben Guebila, Daniel C Morgan, Kimberly Glass, Marieke L. Kuijjer, Dawn L. DeMeo, John Quackenbush.
NAR Genomics and Bioinformatics
doi.org/10.1093/nargab/lqac002.
Abstract Gene regulatory network inference allows for the modeling of genome-scale regulatory processes that are altered during development, in disease, and in response to perturbations. Our group has developed a collection of tools to model various regulatory processes, including transcriptional (PANDA, SPIDER) and post-transcriptional (PUMA) gene regulation, as well as gene regulation in individual samples (LIONESS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EGRET</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/panda/egret/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/panda/egret/</guid>
      <description>Reference Predicting genotype-specific gene regulatory networks
Deborah Weighill, Marouen Ben Guebila, Kimberly Glass, John Quackenbush, John Platig
Genome Research
doi.org/10.1101/gr.275107.120
Abstract Understanding how each person&#39;s unique genotype influences their individual patterns of gene regulation has the potential to improve our understanding of human health and development, and to refine genotype-specific disease risk assessments and treatments. However, the effects of genetic variants are not typically considered when constructing gene regulatory networks, despite the fact that many disease-associated genetic variants are thought to have regulatory effects, including the disruption of transcription factor (TF) binding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DRAGON</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/dragon/</guid>
      <description>Reference DRAGON: Determining Regulatory Associations using Graphical models on multi-Omic Networks
Katherine H Shutta, Deborah Weighill, Rebekka Burkholz, Marouen Ben Guebila, Dawn L DeMeo, Helena U Zacharias, John Quackenbush, Michael Altenbuchinger
OUP Nucleic Acids Research
10.1093/nar/gkac1157
Abstract The increasing quantity of multi-omic data, such as methylomic and transcriptomic profiles collected on the same specimen or even on the same cell, provides a unique opportunity to explore the complex interactions that define cell phenotype and govern cellular responses to perturbations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YARN</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/yarn/</guid>
      <description>Reference Tissue-aware RNA-Seq processing and normalization for heterogeneous and sparse data
Joseph N. Paulson, Cho-Yi Chen, Camila M. Lopes-Ramos, Marieke L. Kuijjer, John Platig, Abhijeet R. Sonawane, Maud Fagny, Kimberly Glass &amp;amp; John Quackenbush
BMC Bioinformatics
doi.org/10.1186/s12859-017-1847-x
Abstract Background
Although ultrahigh-throughput RNA-Sequencing has become the dominant technology for genome-wide transcriptional profiling, the vast majority of RNA-Seq studies typically profile only tens of samples, and most analytical pipelines are optimized for these smaller studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TIGER</title>
      <link>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/tiger/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 08:50:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://netZoo.github.io/zooanimals/tiger/</guid>
      <description>Reference Joint inference of transcription factor activity and context-specific regulatory networks
Chen Chen, Megha Padi
bioRxiv
doi.org/10.1101/2022.12.12.520141
Abstract Transcriptional regulation is a critical process that determines cell fate and disease. One of the challenges in understanding transcriptional regulation is that there is no easy way to infer the main regulators from gene expression data. Many existing methods focus on estimating the activity of individual transcription factors (TFs) using static TF-gene interaction databases, but regulomes are often altered in different cell types and disease conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>